

ROPE ACCESS TECHNICIAN \ WTG

# **Details**

Riga

Latvia

+371 20011237

andrejs.fokins94@gmail.com

DRIVING LICENSE

B category (from 2014)

02/07/1994

#### Skills

Blade Repair

Spot painting

**Professional Attitude** 

Reliable & Punctual

# Languages

English

Latvian

Ukrainian

Russian

# **Hobbies**

Hiking, Reading, Workout

# **Profile**

Hardworking and experienced Rope Access Technician, able to perform a variety of duties with skill. Punctual, hardworking, friendly, outgoing, and committed to providing top-notch services. I'm stress-resistant. Easily cope with any complex work. Quickly learn new materials and skills. I am able to soberly assess the situation and risk.

# **Employment History**

# Rope Access Technician L2, UAB Solwinda

SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

September 2022

Offshore substation platform - HKN

- 1. Dismantling and installation work, stretching awnings, sandblasting.
- 2. Painting jobs, Blasting, Metal spot repair, De-rusting using needle guns and bristle blasters.
  - November 2022 May 2023

Rigs: Noble Highlander, Noble Reacher Noble Resolve Noble Interceptor Noble Resolute Noble Integrator

Changed the name of the logo on the rig "Maersk" to "Noble"

- 1. Painting jobs, De-rusting using needle guns and bristle blasters.
- 2. Stud anchoring, logo mount.
  - June 2023

Offshore substation platform - HKN

- Painting jobs, Blasting, Metal spot repair, De-rusting using needle guns and bristle blasters.
  - July 2023 August 2023

Offshore substation platform - Baltic Eagle

- 1. Dismantling and installation work, stretching awnings, sandblasting.
- 2. Painting jobs, Blasting, Metal spot repair, De-rusting using needle guns and bristle
  - October 2023 November 2023

Offshore substation platform - West Alpha

1. Dismantling and installation work, stretching awnings, sandblasting.

#### Rope Access Technician L2 / Wind Turbine Technician, UAB Gridinta

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

• Onshore - various types of work with Nordex D4k, D3k turbines:

Blade repair - Inspection,

Performed repairs from a platform and used rope access techniques,

Safety blade repair (temporary repair) from ropes.

Maintenance - Inspect or repair wind turbine equipment,

Perform routine maintenance on wind turbines,

Replace worn or malfunctioning components.

 Offshore - wind farm substations (spot painting, painting and sandblasting, rope access)

# Wind Turbine Technitian (Retrofit), Productive Services GmbH (PS)

JULY 2022 - AUGUST 2022

• Offshore - Modernization, re-strengthening of metal structures in nacelle for helipad.

# Rope Access Technician L2, WP Group/Baltic Dia

AUGUST 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021

 Onshore - Worked with Enercon and GE turbines in Germany: Carried out the installation work of installing a ladder inside the turbine, working with rope access techniques

#### Rope Access Technician L1, SIA INDUSTRIALAIS ALPINISMS

FEBRUARY 2020 - JULY 2021

 Onshore - Performed various types of work using rope access techniques as an industrial climber: installation work, painting, cleaning, inspection and washing of windows.

# Wind Turbine Technician, WP Group/Baltic Dia

AUGUST 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

Inspection, sanding and painting of damaged and corroded areas on the wind turbine using a special small platform.

# Mechanic Assembler / Welder, VM-Group Oy - Promeco, Dynamotie 4, 65320 Vaasa, Finland, Vaasa (Finland)

APRIL 2019 - AUGUST 2019

The main direction of production is components and parts for engines, turbines and manifolds for ships and boats.

- reading drawings and electrical schemes
- electrical and mechanical assemblies
- welding MIG/MAG
- creation of different constructions according to the drawings

# Work at the shipyard interior, Kleven Verft AS Klubbenesvegen / DEROSSI, Ulsteinvik 39, Norway, Ulsteinvik (Norway)Ulsteinvik 39, Norway, Ulsteinvik (Norway)

OCTOBER 2018 - APRIL 2019

- interior construction  $\$  Finishing work
- installation of ceiling and walls in accordance with the plan and drawings
- assembly of furniture and interior components

# Mechanic in Experimental Workshop / (Operator in CNC Workshop), LDZ RSS, Riga

FEBRUARY 2016 - OCTOBER 2018

- assembly of metal constructions
- realization of orders of varying complexity
- work with the appropriate tools and equipment
- cnc bending machine

- cnc 3D printer (modeling programs with: Blender, Maya)
- work on the guillotine
- manufacturing
- work with scheme (drawings)
- welding

# Electrician technician, LDZ RSS, Riga

MAY 2014 - FEBRUARY 2016

- diesel locomotive maintenance
- repair according to the established standards
- work with the appropriate tools and equipment
- disassembly and assembly of apparatus (device) and equipment
- repair of electrical equipment in a special workshop
- problem diagnosis
- cyclic work
- launch of a diesel locomotive according to schemes

# **Education**

# RTU (Riga Technical University), Riga

SEPTEMBER 2015 - JUNE 2019

# **Courses**

IRATA Level 2 - (Irata No 2/150548)

**GWO BST (Full)** 

Hailo

**BOSIET (CAEBS)** 

MIST (OPITO)

**B-VCA** 

**OGUK** (Medical cert.)

H2S

**SSG Entry Basic Course** 

SFS6002 Electrical Safety Standard

Driver license cat. B

**EU** passport Holder